<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

 <title>Stefan Ruijsenaars</title>
 <link href="https://www.stefanruijsenaars.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="https://www.stefanruijsenaars.com/"/>
 <updated>2016-11-16T11:41:06-08:00</updated>
 <id>https://www.stefanruijsenaars.com</id>
 <author>
   <name>Stefan Ruijsenaars</name>
   <email>stefan@doxxo.nl</email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>🐟 ❤️</title>
   <link href="https://www.stefanruijsenaars.com/2016/11/15/i-heart-fish/"/>
   <updated>2016-11-15T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
   <id>https://www.stefanruijsenaars.com/2016/11/15/i-heart-fish</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/prison.png&quot; alt=&quot;twitter post&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After learning that a good friend would “rather go to prison than use bash”, I decided to finally give fish a try.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fish, as in &lt;a href=&quot;https://fishshell.com&quot;&gt;fish&lt;/a&gt;, his preferred shell :).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of my developer friends use bash (some of the more hardcore ones use zsh), and personally I have been using bash almost every day since I was a teenager. Despite all of its shortcomings, I have grown very fond of it – besides my browser, it’s probably the place I spend the most time in. But having used fish for a few months as my default shell, I am now a convert, and I likely will remain one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fish comes with a whole bunch of goodies. While most of them are available for bash as well, but with fish they all work out of the box, with no configuration needed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To me, the truly killer ones are the &lt;strong&gt;autosuggestions&lt;/strong&gt; and the &lt;strong&gt;tab completion&lt;/strong&gt;. Fish suggests commands in a smart way, based on your history, previous completion picks, and valid file paths (including &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/fish-shell/fish-shell/issues/22&quot;&gt;implicit cd&lt;/a&gt;). As you type a command, you’ll see the suggestion right after the cursor, in gray. To accept, you only need to press right arrow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fish will also make a great guess whenever you press &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;tab&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;. If there is more than one completion, you can tab through all the possible ones. And when you do it for a command line option, it integrates with the man pages, showing all the available switches. It also does lots and lots of general purpose and program-specific &lt;a href=&quot;http://fishshell.com/docs/current/index.html&quot;&gt;completions&lt;/a&gt; – git, mount, ssh, su, …&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Further &lt;em&gt;awesome&lt;/em&gt; features include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;No hidden settings, all the special features are on by default&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Very fancy colors (256 of them), which truly offer extra visual feedback&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Loooong command history (!)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Skips duplicates in your history&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;For partial commands, the up arrow shows matching commands from your history only&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Wildcards&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A web based configuration interface&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It’s &lt;em&gt;fast&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A fantastic &lt;a href=&quot;http://fishshell.com/docs/current/design.html&quot;&gt;design document&lt;/a&gt; outlining their design philosophy (the “Configurability is the root of all evil” one had me wildly nodding my head)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Backward history search (similar to ctrl+r in bash) using &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jbonjean/re-search&quot;&gt;re-search&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/oh-my-fish/oh-my-fish&quot;&gt;Oh my fish&lt;/a&gt; is also a cool framework for the fish shell, adding such things as git integration (showing your current branch/git status), fancy themes, and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rupa/z&quot;&gt;z&lt;/a&gt; plugin, a fantastic tool that allows you to navigate to your most used directories using fuzzy commands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall this shell is just “the next level of convenience” (also © &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/da_wehner/status/598589852888801282&quot;&gt;Daniel Wehner&lt;/a&gt;), and a true pleasure to use. It’s here to stay for me, and I strongly encourage you to &lt;a href=&quot;https://fishshell.com/#platform_tabs&quot;&gt;give it a try&lt;/a&gt; as well!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just a note: this is not a POSIX shell – you may need to run bash-specific things with &lt;code&gt;bash -c&lt;/code&gt; or use tools like &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/edc/bass&quot;&gt;bass&lt;/a&gt;. Fish also comes with its own scripting language, which I haven’t looked into it yet – I still do my scripting in bash :).&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Back Alley Dance Party</title>
   <link href="https://www.stefanruijsenaars.com/2016/11/08/back-alley-dance-party/"/>
   <updated>2016-11-08T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
   <id>https://www.stefanruijsenaars.com/2016/11/08/back-alley-dance-party</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Here’s a thing me and my friend &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/tretuna&quot;&gt;Tre Ammatuna&lt;/a&gt; made together today – the artwork is blatantly stolen, but until the takedown requests arrive, enjoy blowing up some animals:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/catparty/dancefloor.html&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/backalley.png&quot; alt=&quot;Back Alley Dance Party&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 

</feed>
